[{"id": "5fea422dff048f679a45ab75", "question": "What is a term in Physics for a fundamental constituent of matter?", "answer": "Particle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aded", "question": "In which century did the English Civil War take place?", "answer": "17th", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca81", "question": "From what animal fat was margarine first made from in the US?", "answer": "Beef", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ab1b2904fda37788a9a1dbb", "question": "Who won a Pulitzer Prize for \"Angela's Ashes\"?", "answer": "Frank McCourt", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bd05aedce677f092a9a4018", "question": "In the book \"The Aspen Account\", who is revealed to be dead at the start?", "answer": "Kurt Matthews", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c277", "question": "What is October's birthstone?", "answer": "Opal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca27", "question": "What is the medical term for fainting?", "answer": "Syncope", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c222", "question": "Which type of nut is used to make Nutella?", "answer": "Hazelnut", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015dfc4fe83fe1f2a824b7f", "question": "When was the steam turbine invented?", "answer": "First century A.D.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8bf", "question": "What is the more common name for Axilla?", "answer": "Armpit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a754", "question": "Which four US states begin with the word \"New\"?", "answer": "New Hampshire, New Jersey, New Mexico and New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "590498aecf93664eb1048689", "question": "A statue of Lady Godiva stands in the centre which English city?", "answer": "Coventry", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c023", "question": "In what city was fashion designer Gianni Versace killed?", "answer": "Miami Beach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed6", "question": "What colour is chablis?\u00a0", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c81a", "question": "In what part of the body would you find sebum?", "answer": "The skin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a9e93da7ccba3ffe45786cb", "question": "What was Buddy Holly's birth name?", "answer": "Charles Hardin Holley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067ecaff9c0647b50a807e", "question": "To what age did the US state of Hawaii change the legal smoking age on January 1, 2016?", "answer": "21", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c853", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find parietal cells?", "answer": "The stomach", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c16e", "question": "What is the official residence of the Lord Mayor of London?", "answer": "Mansion House", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abb8", "question": "Lilongwe is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Malawi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c063", "question": "In 1892, 15-year-old Alonzo \"Lonnie\" Clayton became the youngest winner of which sporting event?", "answer": "The Kentucky Derby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa49", "question": "Which ocean is The Gulf Stream\u00a0in?", "answer": "The Atlantic\u00a0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b47e", "question": "What two countries fought in the Battle of the Plains of Abraham?", "answer": "Great Britain and France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fcd", "question": "What TV show did \"Lou Grant\" spin off from?", "answer": "The Mary Tyler Moore Show", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab96cb86faa38a764be524", "question": "Which car company did Christian von Koenigsegg found in 1994?", "answer": "Koenigsegg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59524772736d4be723796b72", "question": "Approximately 7.5 million of what can be created from a cord of wood?", "answer": "Toothpicks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e26", "question": "What did Benjamin Britten write the \"Young Person's Guide to\" in 1945?", "answer": "The Orchestra", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8be", "question": "What German city is home to a statue called \"The Town Musicians\"?", "answer": "Bremen", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397ed", "question": "Which more successful group did Mick Abrahams leave in 1969 to form Blodwyn Pig?", "answer": "Jethro Tull", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e8a89de404ad935a7e1a641", "question": "What do you call a baby female horse?", "answer": "Filly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af93", "question": "General George H. Thomas was nicknamed the \"Rock of Chickamauga\" during what war?", "answer": "Civil War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c67e", "question": "What type of chemical bonding occurs between hydrogen and chlorine?", "answer": "Covalent", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397c9", "question": "In the 1994 movie \"Jumanji\", a stampede is released, what is the last animal to appear?", "answer": "Rhinoceros", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523dca736d4be723796b48", "question": "What year did the last Province or Territory join Canada?", "answer": "1999", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad5", "question": "How many zeroes are in the number one trillion?", "answer": "12", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ea0", "question": "Since 1961, where have Margo Magee, Tommie Thompson, and Lu Ann Powers lived?", "answer": "Apartment 3-G", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b822", "question": "What psychoanalyst smoked 20 cigars per day?", "answer": "Sigmund Freud", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049990cf93664eb1048693", "question": "Which famous actor is honored with a statue in Leicester Square?", "answer": "Charlie Chaplin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b13", "question": "Who did Lionel Richie duet with on the 1981 #1 smash \"Endless Love\"?", "answer": "Diana Ross", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133914d", "question": "Who was the Greek god of blacksmiths?", "answer": "Hephaestus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff51cf7ff04d658268c9320", "question": "What fraction of a person did slaves originally count as in the U.S. Constitution?", "answer": "3/5", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c515", "question": "What disease is the focus of oncology?", "answer": "Cancer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b386", "question": "Which country was known as British Honduras prior to 1973?", "answer": "Belize", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc1716de0eb824d4052df", "question": "What is the largest glacier in North America?", "answer": "Bering Glacier in Alaska holds the record as the largest glacier in North America.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b3235f5bf195a31e15d73b4", "question": "Who played the electric piano on the Beatles track \"Get Back\"?", "answer": "Billy Preston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5efa93f1ccb363a2cbc52278", "question": "What is the largest landlocked county in England?", "answer": "Shropshire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133939a", "question": "How many Oscar nominations did the 1995 movie \"Apollo 13\" receive?", "answer": "Nine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015dfd6fe83fe1f2a824b81", "question": "Who wrote the first algorithm intended to be carried out by a machine?", "answer": "Ada Lovelace", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec8", "question": "Mr. Giles French was a character on which US TV show in the late 1960's?", "answer": "Family Affair", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396a6", "question": "Who played the role of T.E. Lawrence in the 1962 movie \"Lawrence of Arabia\"?", "answer": "Peter O'Toole", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe377f90ada16518afdc04e", "question": "Who was the founder of Cartier?", "answer": "Louis-Frantois Cartier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b83", "question": "What is the name of the evolutionary biologist who wrote \"The God Delusion\"?", "answer": "Richard Dawkins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf35", "question": "What number is at 12 o'clock on a dartboard?", "answer": "20", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f200ff048f679a45aab5", "question": "What type of cloud is characterized by thin, wispy strands?", "answer": "Cirrus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e6b5f9fb6c85e9e634ff46", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed \"Land of 10,000 Lakes\"?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefc3ae6ce05a3942286f26", "question": "John Paul Jones was the bassist and keyboardist for what rock band?", "answer": "Led Zeppelin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339466", "question": "Who played the role of Warden Hal Moores in the 1999 movie \"The Green Mile\"?", "answer": "James Cromwell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1a2", "question": "Who said \"Too much of a good thing can be wonderful\"?", "answer": "Mae West", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c17d", "question": "What is the opposite of an utopia?", "answer": "Dystopia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff2148831a458464a93c458", "question": "A sentence, verse, etc., that includes all the letters of the alphabet is called what?", "answer": "Pangram", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbae", "question": "What term for a Bigfoot creature comes from the Salish Indian word meaning \"wild man\"?", "answer": "Sasquatch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394fb", "question": "In the movie \"300\", how many of the 300 Spartan warriors survive?", "answer": "One", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e79", "question": "During what war was the novel \"Catch-22\" set?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c114", "question": "What year was Canadian figure skater, Elvis Stojko, born?", "answer": "1972", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0fe", "question": "In what country was Adolf Hitler born?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b323475bf195a31e15d73a6", "question": "What is the narrow, inland sea, separates the western Asia from northeastern Africa?", "answer": "Red sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bedf", "question": "Who won the US Open men's tennis title in 1990 at the age of just 19?", "answer": "Pete Sampras", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8de", "question": "In which hand is the Statue of Liberty holding a torch?", "answer": "Right hand", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339211", "question": "What is the name of the president in the movie \"Mars Attacks\"?", "answer": "James Dale", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e05", "question": "What movie was partially inspired by Jean Shepherd's unpublished story \"Flick's Tongue\"?", "answer": "A Christmas Story", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7ca88877e98cb97778a06", "question": "What country is made up of 3,000 islands, the largest being Honshu, Hokkaido, Kyushu and Shikoku?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a816", "question": "The two largest islands in the Mediterranean Sea are part of what country?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b3ade662d71a53650fe1", "question": "What unique quirk did Fr\u00e9d\u00e9ric Chopin have?", "answer": "He preferred to play in the dark.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d6e", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"A Tale of the Christ\"?", "answer": "Ben-Hur", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b808", "question": "What relative does a Russian call \"babushka\"?", "answer": "Grandmother", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ba", "question": "What is measured in Poise?", "answer": "Viscosity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf6d", "question": "What are you frightened of if you are Alektorophobic?", "answer": "Chickens", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e2", "question": "What year was the first book of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" series first published?", "answer": "1980", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e4", "question": "In what country was the \"Michelin Guide\" first published in 1900?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390f6", "question": "What is the full name of writer H. G. Wells?", "answer": "Herbert George Wells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b8", "question": "Who directed the 1980 movie \"The Blues Brothers\"?", "answer": "John Landis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be83", "question": "What instrument did bandleader Glenn Miller play?", "answer": "Trombone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b075", "question": "US flags flew at half-staff following the assassination of what Israeli prime minister in 1995?", "answer": "Yitzhak Rabin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "596dfee79616e6c6d4eba4fd", "question": "The Artful Dodger is a character from which novel? ", "answer": "Oliver Twist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388a7", "question": "What George Orwell book foresees Oceania, Eurasia and Eastasia?", "answer": "1984", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0ab", "question": "What kind of a head does a Hieracosphinx possess?", "answer": "Hawk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6008db6ef4f3bc4a292f8617", "question": "Which country first settled land that would become the colony of Delaware?", "answer": "In 1638, Swedish settlers founded the first colony of New Sweden, which was later taken over by the Dutch and then the British.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133954f", "question": "Who was the last known survivor from the planet Melmac?", "answer": "Alf", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6018bbf3d96d05b23b281652", "question": "The 1707 Acts of Union was an event that combined what?", "answer": "England and Scotland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fc854a6abc30a8194e188a9", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Jaws\"?", "answer": "Peter Benchley", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339750", "question": "Who won an Oscar for her role in the movie \"Annie Hall\"?", "answer": "Diane Keaton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b787", "question": "What food is usually left out for Santa Claus on Christmas Eve?", "answer": "Milk and cookies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b390", "question": "In 1946, Yvon Petra was the last Wimbledon champion to do what?", "answer": "Wear trousers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a699", "question": "What are the 4 US state capitols and states that begin with the same letter?", "answer": "Dover Delaware, Honolulu Hawaii, Indianapolis Indiana, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cbc", "question": "What TV show featured the fictional \"The Mystic Knights of the Sea\" fraternity?", "answer": "Amos 'n' Andy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b00d", "question": "The Titanic sank while on its way to what city?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ae7", "question": "Who composed the Christmas carol \"Silent Night\"?", "answer": "Franz Xaver Gruber", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4ed", "question": "What process does milk undergo to become yogurt?", "answer": "Bacterial fermentation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a464", "question": "Mount Rushmore is located near which town in South Dakota?", "answer": "Keystone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefc29f6ce05a3942286f1b", "question": "In the Clint Eastwood film, \"The Dead Pool,\" who plays the roll of Johnny Squares?", "answer": "Jim Carrey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f2", "question": "Who sang the title song for the 1978 suspense film \"Eyes of Laura Mars\"?", "answer": "Barbra Streisand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0a7", "question": "In October 2005, Angela Merkel became what European country's first female chancellor?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c28f", "question": "Which sex has the shorter human vocals?", "answer": "The female", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5be581145415ba52ed6f0abd", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The History of Mr Polly\"?", "answer": "H. G. Wells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59a7f51a6f5f79087132fb3d", "question": "What do British people call zucchini?", "answer": "Courgette", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6af", "question": "What letter represents the speed of light in physics notations?", "answer": "c", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58c8a83b90aac110e416708c", "question": "Who said \"He that drinks his cider alone, let him catch his horse alone.\"?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65d991f3c0ead6880d61e", "question": "Who was Moses' sister in the Bible?", "answer": "Miriam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b949", "question": "What type of race is the Belmont Stakes?", "answer": "Horse race", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e5d", "question": "What literary work inspired Sting's \"Moon Over Bourbon Street\" song?", "answer": "Interview with a Vampire", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c80dfbde8045e48466cd", "question": "Tercel is the name for the male of which animal?", "answer": "Hawk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339651", "question": "What kind of animal is the title character in the 1998 movie \"Paulie\"?", "answer": "Parrot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f1", "question": "What Agatha Christie novel was made up of two parts - England and Egypt?", "answer": "Death on the Nile", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1fe", "question": "What is Pat Benatar's birth name?", "answer": "Patricia Mae Andrzejewski", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3674ff048f679a45ab0e", "question": "What vegetable grows fast enough that you can hear it?", "answer": "Rhubarb", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c7a6877e98cb977789d4", "question": "Sutherland Falls is located in what country?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6ab", "question": "Which country does paella come from?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398d2", "question": "The Flintstones lived in what city?", "answer": "Bedrock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8f8", "question": "What is the only Canadian province whose borders form a rectangle?", "answer": "Saskatchewan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e3b", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"Into the Primitive\"?", "answer": "The Call of the Wild", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b041", "question": "In 1626, what island was purchased by Peter Minuit from the natives for goods valued at $24?", "answer": "Manhattan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3d6", "question": "The tune \"Rhapsody in Blue\" was first performed in which year?", "answer": "1924", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a237", "question": "What band released an album entitled \"Business as Usual\"?", "answer": "Men at Work", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c352877e98cb97778994", "question": "Which U.S. state is famous for its bluebonnets?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef659b6ce05a3942286e6f", "question": "Who was the first actress to wear pants to the Oscars?", "answer": "Barbara Streisand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ded33fea2747c8aff16d46", "question": "What type of a clothing item is a \"Sam Browne\"?", "answer": "A belt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe733e0eec85e375820b227", "question": "What agreement, signed on September 27, 1940, created the Axis Powers?", "answer": "Tripartite Pact", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133891a", "question": "What Italian city was Michelangelo raised in?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015f7f7fe83fe1f2a824c28", "question": "Who was the first President of the United States to attend a St. Patrick's Day parade?", "answer": "In 1948, Harry S. Truman, the 33rd President of the United States, attended a St. Patrick's Day parade in New York City.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d474e4f8e329de4f8778a1", "question": "The \"Associated Powers\" was the original proposed name of what organization?", "answer": "The United Nations", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339299", "question": "What is the main difference between the character Starbuck in the 70's version of \"Battlestar Galact", "answer": "Starbuck is a female in the reboot and a male in the 70's version", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b35b01dd7bf43be5e7ad", "question": "A group of elephants is called what?", "answer": "A parade or memory", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab183cbaab681b09292188", "question": "Which racing team introduced a six-wheeled race car in 1974 and began racing it in 1976?", "answer": "Tyrrell Racing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a10e", "question": "What was Spencer Tracy's last film?", "answer": "Guess Who's Coming to Dinner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af80", "question": "Who did Dwight Eisenhower defeat twice in presidential elections during the 1950s?", "answer": "Adlai Stevenson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac57", "question": "Which ship was Titanic's sister ship?", "answer": "The Olympic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd40", "question": "Who has been the pole sitter at a record six Indy 500s, from 1979 to 1991?", "answer": "Rick Mears", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3a3", "question": "What three-letter word means the smallest piece of information used by a computer?", "answer": "Bit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133978f", "question": "What did Def Leppard drummer Rick Allen lose in a 1984 auto accident?", "answer": "An arm", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd31", "question": "Which Internet personality used the catchphrase, \"I remember it, so you don't have to!\"", "answer": "The Nostalgia Critic", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e6bc92fb6c85e9e634ff5e", "question": "Majorca is the largest of which island group?", "answer": "Balearic Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6012185063c99d48cd169af0", "question": "In Florida, only on Sundays, it is illegal for a single woman to do what?", "answer": "Skydive", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e4e", "question": "Whose tombstone bears the inscription \"Here Lies One Whose Name Was Writ in Water\"?", "answer": "John Keats", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4fb", "question": "How many minutes does it take sunlight to reach Earth?", "answer": "8", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6b9", "question": "The city of Muskogee is located in which US state?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fffa6f973838c5c8a417f34", "question": "A crossbreed between a donkey and the zebra is known as what?", "answer": "Zonkey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339056", "question": "In the opera \"La traviata\", what was Violetta's occupation?", "answer": "Courtesan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f8c601dd7bf43be5e848", "question": "Who said, \"I don't make jokes. I just watch the government and report the facts\"?", "answer": "Will Rogers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdc5", "question": "What is the traditional herb in pesto sauce?", "answer": "Basil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338936", "question": "Whose best-selling diary was written by Helen Fielding?", "answer": "Bridget Jones's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e61", "question": "Who provided the original voice for The Iron Giant?", "answer": "Vin Diesel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9e2", "question": "A pike most resembles what kind of weapon?", "answer": "Spear", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d7", "question": "Which song became synonymous with \"The Bridge on the River Kwai\"?", "answer": "The Colonel Bogey March", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db76d20ab2c8f322317fe7", "question": "In which ocean or sea are the Seychelles?", "answer": "Indian Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febb0a17e83c707845b2106", "question": "Which famous retailer started out as a mail-order watch business?", "answer": "Sears", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef65ff6ce05a3942286e73", "question": "Which famous actress was the first Tool Time Girl on \"Home Improvement\"?", "answer": "Pamela Anderson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a6c020565ad31a57c7de", "question": "What city is the home of the Liberty Bell?", "answer": "Philadelphia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b7ffb733a3a814d89068c65", "question": "Who wanted you to \"Shake Your Groove Thing\"?", "answer": "Peaches & Herb", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe1ebf7145fb29466707383", "question": "What is a 10 letter word meaning \"to mix or blend together in a homogeneous body\"?", "answer": "Amalgamate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133973b", "question": "What do the letters stand for in the band CCR?", "answer": "Creedence Clearwater Revival", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396f9", "question": "What color is Spock's blood?", "answer": "Green", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3b7", "question": "What are categorized as the biological class \"aves\"?", "answer": "Birds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339515", "question": "Which 1992 western starring Clint Eastwood, Morgan Freeman and Gene Hackman won the Oscar for Best Picture?", "answer": "Unforgiven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d00", "question": "What letter accounts for one of every eight used in written English?", "answer": "E", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6fc", "question": "What dermatological problem do you most likely have if you have over secreting sebaceous glands?", "answer": "Acne", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60062c20c9d816e292245c29", "question": "English artist Andy Brown created a portrait of Queen Elizabeth II using what?", "answer": "English artist Andy Brown created a portrait of Queen Elizabeth II out of 1000 used and unused tea bags.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7ca97877e98cb97778a07", "question": "Which city is Seattle's sister city in Japan?", "answer": "Kobe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4de6206d333868d34d714", "question": "Who is known for running through the streets crying Eureka?", "answer": "Archimedes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b19c", "question": "What dog breed was the official 1972 Summer Olympics mascot?", "answer": "Dachshund", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600240c94be4723ccac22168", "question": "In Tom Clancy's Jack Ryan novels, Jack graduates from what college?", "answer": "Boston College", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af28", "question": "Who founded the city of Singapore?", "answer": "Stamford Raffles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c6a", "question": "In \"Alice in Wonderland\", what is the last thing that disappears on the Cheshire Cat?", "answer": "Its smile", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd62", "question": "What delicacy comes from Wagyu cattle?", "answer": "Kobe beef", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339124", "question": "Jean de Brunhoff created the appearance of Babar the Elephant, but who invented the character?", "answer": "Cecile de Brunhoff", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c422", "question": "What birds do Chinese and Japanese fisherman commonly use?", "answer": "Cormorants", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c40b", "question": "Where do bumblebees normally nest?", "answer": "Underground", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b347", "question": "What toy was released in 1958 creating an instant craze among children?", "answer": "The Hula Hoop", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338990", "question": "What Beatrix Potter character has roasted grasshopper for supper after failing to catch minnows?", "answer": "Mr. Jeremy Fisher", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a922", "question": "What part of Britain has Cadwalader's red dragon on its flag?", "answer": "Wales", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b416", "question": "What year did Sierra Leone gain its independence from the UK?", "answer": "1961", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d66", "question": "What is the subtitle of J.R.R. Tolkien's \"The Hobbit\"?", "answer": "There and Back Again", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6589bae7e414034b5aef3", "question": "Where did yoga originate?", "answer": "India", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a468", "question": "In which city would you find the Hermitage Museum?", "answer": "Saint Petersburg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a55a", "question": "What is the capital of Alaska?", "answer": "Juneau", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6996320565ad31a57c745", "question": "According to the Bible, who was the father of Arphaxad?", "answer": "Shem", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf37", "question": "Papaphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "The pope", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a72120565ad31a57c7e5", "question": "What was Susan B. Anthony and Elizabeth Cady Stanton\u2019s newspaper named?", "answer": "\"The Revolution\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b200", "question": "Whose US presidential campaign was targeted by the famous \"Daisy Girl\" negative TV ad?", "answer": "Barry Goldwater's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a60c", "question": "In which county of Ireland would you find the Twelve Bens mountain range?", "answer": "Galway", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdbe", "question": "What is traditionally the main fruit ingredient in a rickey?", "answer": "Limes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6018bc96d96d05b23b281658", "question": "At which hospital did the first heart transplant take place?", "answer": "Groote Schuur Hospital, Cape Town, South Africa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a235", "question": "In which movie did Madonna play the role of \"Gloria Tatlock\"?", "answer": "Shanghai Surprise", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339050", "question": "Which Russian writer composed \"Peter and the Wolf\"?", "answer": "Sergei Prokofiev", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d1e", "question": "Who composed \"5th Symphony\"?", "answer": "Ludwig van Beethoven", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d2", "question": "In the TV show \"Knight Rider\", what does K.I.T.T.'s name stand for?", "answer": "Knight Industries Two Thousand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59774586284458f1d7854436", "question": "What ancient Greek god/goddess represented Necromancy?", "answer": "Hecate", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59e6bb49fb6c85e9e634ff53", "question": "Which American female vocalist had a hit in 1985 with \"We Don't Need Another Hero\"?", "answer": "Tina Turner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8ab2b01dd7bf43be5e764", "question": "What does the term \"contrived patina\" mean?", "answer": "A weathered-looking surface", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b77e", "question": "What kind of sporting event is divided into chukkas?", "answer": "A polo match", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa9296ce05a3942286edc", "question": "What musical did the song \"We Need a Little Christmas\" originate from?", "answer": "Mame", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339492", "question": "Who directed the 1999 movie \"The Green Mile\"?", "answer": "Frank Darabont", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5a3", "question": "How many ounces are there in a pound?", "answer": "16", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c5", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is Smithers' first name?", "answer": "Waylon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e3", "question": "What did Harry Stone wear under his judge's robes on the TV show \"Night Court\"?", "answer": "Blue jeans", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a549", "question": "What river was dammed to create Lake Chickamauga?", "answer": "Tennessee River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8aeed01dd7bf43be5e784", "question": "How long is the hour hand on Big Ben?", "answer": "9 feet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc274ec223966ae8f8876", "question": "Which Disney princess had two stepsisters, Anastasia and Drizella?", "answer": "Cinderella", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8cc", "question": "Burning potassium has what color flame?", "answer": "Purple", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c9af877e98cb977789fa", "question": "In which city will you find the Tiergarten Park?", "answer": "Berlin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa580cc73aa70ea0b70b38", "question": "After a write-in contest, what did Alaska select as its motto?", "answer": "Juneau journalist, Richard Peter, suggested \"North to the Future,\" which was selected as Alaska's official state motto in 1967.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b007", "question": "In 1917, the US entered what war?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b74b", "question": "What A-word means the same as toxophilite?", "answer": "Archer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd9725723c87fd04dd15e52", "question": "In which country was the umbrella invented?", "answer": "China", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad6", "question": "Dustin Hoffman earned his first Oscar nomination for what movie?", "answer": "The Graduate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394ea", "question": "What TV show began with the words \"There is nothing wrong with your television set.\"?", "answer": "The Outer Limits", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338887", "question": "What is the singular of graffiti?", "answer": "Graffito", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ab99ca021a8909e5c332d37", "question": "Which organ secretes insulin?", "answer": "The pancreas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a6e", "question": "What pair of Disney rodents made their debut in the 1943 cartoon \"Private Pluto\"?", "answer": "Chip 'n' Dale", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c5", "question": "What are the three main sections of an insect's body?", "answer": "The head, the abdomen and the thorax", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad92", "question": "What event prevented the lighting of the National Christmas Tree in 1979?", "answer": "The Iran Hostage Crisis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d7c", "question": "What Top Gun actor loses his left arm in the movies \"Total Recall\" and \"Starship Troopers\"?", "answer": "Michael Ironside", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febae607e83c707845b20f5", "question": "What was Uranus originally called?", "answer": "Georgium Sidus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c870", "question": "What is a Chinese gooseberry?", "answer": "A kiwifruit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e99ffe83fe1f2a824be9", "question": "In 1986, a U.S. court of appeals ruled that what magic-practising movement qualifies as a religion?", "answer": "Wicca", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe73e5eeec85e375820b274", "question": "Antananarivo is the capital of which large island?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0b9", "question": "In 1901, William McKinley was assassinated in which US state?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecca43ec223966ae8f8898", "question": "Paul D. Hubbard is the quarterback who is credited with inventing the modern huddle. What affliction did he suffer from?", "answer": "He was deaf and created the huddle so that he can hear teammates better and hide plays from the defending squad.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3d9", "question": "Who was Martina Navratilova's usual ladies doubles partner in the 1980's?\u00a0", "answer": "Pam Shriver\u00a0", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bd1", "question": "Which ABBA song won the 1974 Eurovision Song Contest?", "answer": "Waterloo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d119d74fea7fe947a22291", "question": "Who was known as the \"Clown Prince\" of basketball?", "answer": "Meadowlark Lemon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1fd", "question": "Which continent was host to the 1992 Summer and Winter Olympic Games?", "answer": "Europe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a2", "question": "What chain introduced \"the Blizzard\" in 1985?", "answer": "Dairy Queen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be8c", "question": "Who began his career as \"the Cherokee Kid\", the trick roper in Texas Jack's Wild West Circus?", "answer": "Will Rogers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b184", "question": "What year was US President Ronald Reagan born?", "answer": "1911", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133955d", "question": "What is the sport in the movie \"Field of Dreams\"?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e6", "question": "Which actor played the role of Trinity in the movie \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "Carrie Anne-Moss", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59049b8ccf93664eb10486a0", "question": "What company publishes \"The Walking Dead\" comic book series?", "answer": "Image Comics", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7a3", "question": "At what age did inventor Alexander Graham Bell immigrate to Canada?", "answer": "23", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a85", "question": "Who flew from England to America in a giant peach carried by seagulls?", "answer": "James", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0b5", "question": "With which hand do soldiers salute?", "answer": "Right", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bba0", "question": "Where would you most likely find a \"spinnaker\"?", "answer": "On a sailboat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b36e", "question": "What is Ronald Reagan's middle name?", "answer": "Wilson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f5", "question": "What TV mother has presided over the longest-running American sitcom ever?", "answer": "Marge Simpson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909ccb3bb53d1af658864e2", "question": "Which composer wrote the classical piece \"Messiah\"?", "answer": "George Frideric Handel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4a5b49076251badbeab4", "question": "Six Flags, the famous Texas amusement park, was named after what?", "answer": "The six governments that have ruled Texas -- Specifically, France, Spain, Mexico, the Confederacy, Texas and the U.S.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c756", "question": "In the culinary world, what does MSG short for?", "answer": "Monosodium glutamate", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339661", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who sold a monorail to the city of Springfield?", "answer": "Lyle Lanley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6000ed209a72b906b34e3ce9", "question": "Fissures, vents and plugs are all associated with which geological feature?", "answer": "Volcano", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ef3", "question": "Which member of \"the Rat Pack\" was married to a Kennedy?", "answer": "Peter Lawford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd820ecd0de9af39e9d46a0", "question": "What state is home to US' oldest newspaper still being printed?", "answer": "Connecticut", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e6bb64fb6c85e9e634ff54", "question": "Whose fifth album was called \"Different Class\"?", "answer": "Pulp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d9", "question": "What is a somnambulist?", "answer": "Sleepwalker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5967613d2b59efe0e9417ea2", "question": "The song \"Good Girl\" was the 12th Top 20 hit for what artist?", "answer": "Carrie Underwood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f84", "question": "The Michael Douglas film \"A Perfect Murder\" is a remake of what 1950s thriller?", "answer": "Dial M for Murder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338efe", "question": "Whose right-hand man is Mr. Smee?", "answer": "Captain Hook", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339da7", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Seven Days in May\"?", "answer": "Fredric March", "category": "entertainment"}]